ZIPCODE	Postal code 4 Baseline visit 1
GENDER	Gender (1=male, 2=female)
GROUP_SIZE_CAT	Group size in categories (0-200=1, 200-300=2, 300-400=3 ... 1300-1400=13, 1400-1500=14, 1500+=15)
AGE_CAT	Age in categories (15-20=1, 20-25=2, 25-30=3 ... 85-90 = 15, 90-95=16, 95+=17)
AGE_T1	Age at T1
AGE_T2	Age at T2
BMI_T1	Body Mass Index (kg/M^2) at baseline as mean (T1)
WEIGHT_T1	Weight in kg at second assessment as mean (T1)
HIP_T1	Hip circumference in cm at baseline as mean (T1)
WAIST_T1	Waist circumference in cm at baseline as mean T1)
HEIGHT_T1	Height in cm at baseline as mean (T1)
BMI_T2	Body Mass Index (kg/M^2) at second assessment as mean (T2)
WEIGHT_T2	Weight in kg at second assessment as mean (T2)
HIP_T2	Hip circumference in cm at second assessment as mean (T2)
WAIST_T2	Waist circumference in cm at second assessment as mean (T2)
HEIGHT_T2	Height in cm at second assessment as mean (T2)
EDUCATION_LOWER_T1	Education at baseline in percentage where the highest obtained degree is lower education (ranging from no education to junior general secondary education) (T1)
EDUCATION_LOWER_T2	Education at second assessment in percentage where the highest obtained degree is lower education (ranging from no education to junior general secondary education) (T2)
WORK_T1	Paid work (for at least a few hours a week) at baseline in percentage (T1)
WORK_T2	Paid work (for at least a few hours a week) at second assessment in percentage (T2)
LOW_QUALITY_OF_LIFE_T1	Low quality of life (poor/mediocre) at baseline in percentage (T1)
LOW_QUALITY_OF_LIFE_T2	Low quality of life (poor/mediocre) at second assessment in percentage (T2)
DBP_T1	Diastolic Blood Pressure in mm hg at baseline as mean (T1)
DBP_T2	Diastolic Blood Pressure in mm hg at second assessment as mean (T2)
HBF_T1	Pulse rate in beats per minute at baseline as mean (T1)
HBF_T2	Pulse rate in beats per minute at second assessment as mean (T2)
MAP_T1	Mean Average Pressure at baseline as mean (T1)
MAP_T2	Mean Average Pressure at second assessment as mean (T2)
SBP_T1	Systolic Blood Pressure in mm hg at baseline as mean (T1)
SBP_T2	Systolic Blood Pressure in mm hg at second assessment as mean (T2)
HTN_MED_T1	Hypertension medication at baseline first visit in percentage (T1)
CHO_T1	Cholesterol (mmol/L) assessed on samples from baseline as mean (T1)
GLU_T1	Glucose (mmol/L) assessed on samples from baseline as mean (T1)
CHO_T2	Cholesterol (mmol/L) assessed on samples from second assessment second visit as mean (T2)
GLU_T2	Glucose (mmol/L) assessed on samples from second assessment as mean (T2)
RESPIRATORY_DISEASE_T1	Respiratory disease at baseline in percentage (T1)
PACKYEARS	Cumulative smoking history: 1 packyear = 20 cigarettes per day for 1 year (or 10 cigarettes for 2 years, or 1 cigarette for 20 years). NB. Cigars are regarded as 3 cigarettes. (T1)
SMOKING	Currently smoking at baseline in percentage (T1)
METABOLIC_DISORDER_T1	Metabolic disorder at baseline in percentage (T1)
METABOLIC_DISORDER_T2	Metabolic disorder at second assessment in percentage (T2)
LLDS	Lifelines Diet Score as continuous variable, with a range between 0 and 48, at baseline as mean (T1)
Quintile_LLDS	Lifelines Diet Score as categorical variable, with Q1 referring to poorest and Q5 referring to highest diet quality as mean (T1)
MWK_VAL	Minutes of weekly physical activity on moderate and vigorous intensity level at baseline as mean (T1)
SCOR_VAL	Score for weekly physical activity on moderate and vigorous intensity level, based on the sum of minutes per activity times the intensity of the specific activity at baseline as mean (T1)
MWK_NO_VAL	Minutes of weekly physical activity on moderate and vigorous intensity level, in leisure time and commuting domains (but not occupational) at baseline as mean (T1)
SCOR_NO_VAL	Score for weekly physical activity on moderate and vigorous intensity level, in leisure time and commuting domains (but not occupational), based on the sum of minutes per activity times the intensity of the specific activity at baseline as mean (T1)
PREGNANCIES	Number of times participant has given birth at baseline as mean (T1)
OSTEOARTHRITIS_T1	Joint degradation (osteoarthritis) at baseline in percentage (T1)
SLEEP_QUALITY	Poor sleep quality as measured through the PSQI at baseline in percentage (T1)
DIAG_CFS_CDC	Fulfill CDC Chronic Fatigue Syndrome criteria in percentage (T2)
DIAG_FIBROMYALGIA_ACR	Fulfill ACR Fibromyalgia criteria in percentage (T2)
DIAG_IBS_ROME3	Fulfill ROMEIII Irritable bowel syndrome criteria in percentage (T2)
C_SUM_T1	Sum of all items within facet Competence. Complete cases only, as mean (T1)
A_SUM_T1	Sum of all items within facet Anger-hostility. Complete cases only, as mean (T1)
SC_SUM_T1	Sum of all items within facet Self-consciousness. Complete cases only, as mean (T1)
I_SUM_T1	Sum of all items within facet Impulsivity. Complete cases only, as mean (T1)
E_SUM_T1	Sum of all items within facet Extraversion. Complete cases only, as mean (T1)
SD_SUM_T1	Sum of all items within facet Self-discipline. Complete cases only, as mean (T1)
V_SUM_T1	Sum of all items within facet Vulnerability. Complete cases only, as mean (T1)
D_SUM_T1	Sum of all items within facet Deliberation. Complete cases only, as mean (T1)
LTE_SUM_T1	Total number of stressful life events that happened to participant in the past year at baseline as mean (T1)
LDI_SUM_T1	Total amount of stress from long-term/chronic stressors experienced by the participant at baseline as mean (T1)
LTE_SUM_T2	Total number of stressful life events that happened to participant in the past year at second assessment as mean (T2)
LDI_SUM_T2	Total amount of stress from long-term/chronic stressors experienced by the participant at second assessment as mean (T2)
NSES_YEAR	Year for which the NSES score was calculated as mean
NSES	Neighborhood socio-economic status score according to CBS Statistics Netherlands, based on inhabitants’ educational level, income and job prospective as mean
MENTAL_DISORDER_T1	Cumalitive mean diagnosis of major depressive disorder, dysthymia, generalized anxiety disorder, panic disorder, agoraphobia and social anxiety disorder / social phobia at baseline in percentage (T1)
MENTAL_DISORDER_T2	Cumalitive mean diagnosis of major depressive disorder, dysthymia, generalized anxiety disorder, panic disorder, agoraphobia and social anxiety disorder / social phobia at second assessment in percentage (T2)